opera-mini.net 2009-04-17

# Opera: Privacy Statement

The Opera browser offers excellent features for the protection of privacy and security when using Opera in the internet environment. It is the policy of Opera Software to process personal data for purposes that are objectively justified by Opera Software's service and to perform the processing in accordance with fundamental respect for the right to privacy, including the need to protect personal integrity and private life and to ensure that personal data are of adequate quality.

## Privacy policies

This policy contains general information regarding privacy in Opera. For privacy policies and questions specifically related to OperaBrowser, MyOpera, OperaMini and OperaMail, please see the links below:

  * Privacy in the Opera desktop browser
  * Privacy in the Opera Mini browser
  * Privacy on MyOpera.com 
  * Privacy on Opera Web Mail
  * Privacy of customer data
  * Privacy on Our Web Sites

## Processing

Personal data is only collected, stored, used and transferred for specific purposes mentioned in the privacy policies. Opera collects user submitted information, IP-addresses, usage patterns and the point in time when the user visits Operas website or uses Operas services.

## Purposes

Processing of personal data shall only be done for purposes of running, debugging, maintenance and/or optimization of service and/or to maintain customer relationship.

Analysis of web usage (for purposes of debugging, maintenance and optimization of service) shall never be done on a basis that reveal usage patterns of individual users, but shall be done by aggregating data, anonymizing individual identities.

## Access

Opera Software has strict restriction on access to user data. Only a limited number of Opera employees have access.

## Transfer

Please note: Opera Software cooperates with Hitslink.com, Advertising.com and E-journal. Hitslink is established in USA and have entered into the Safe Harbor-agreement, which entail that Hitslink must ensure an adequate standard for privacy protection. Advertising.com and E-journal are Norwegian companies that must comply with Norwegian Personal Data laws and regulations.

Opera Software does not control and has no responsibility for the privacy and security practices and policies of these third parties and their sites. Check the particular site and/or business for more information. It is the responsibility of the user to use caution before sharing personal information via forms and other methods used by third parties and their websites.

Users can choose not to use Hitslink.com services, **see link to instructions.**

## Correction and rectification

Users of Opera Software's products and services have the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided:

  * Registered users can use this form
  * All visitors can send mail to the postal address listed on the contact page

## Rentention and deletion

Opera Software deletes personal information when all purposes of the processing of the personal information are fulfilled.

## Reviews

Policies are reviewed regularly to ensure that the policies are followed. Any non conformance regards the policies will be corrected without unnecessary delay.

## Security

Opera Software strictly protects the security of personal information within the confines of the Opera domain, and honors the users' choices for its intended use. We carefully protect users' data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, alteration, or destruction. We protect user data from disclosure, with exception only in matters where designated by law or court order.

## Children's guidelines

Opera Software provides interactive environments on the Internet to enable members to express themselves and share their ideas and interests by creating and participating in discussion-based virtual communities. Opera.com, Opera.no, and OperaSoftware.com make no guarantees that children can not enter these sites and present both online and offline contact information without parental consent or notification. Further, there is no guarantee that children will not post such information in a public forum. Therefore, we encourage children to include their parents in the registration process, and we encourage parents to read this privacy statement before allowing their children on line.

## Contact information

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, privacy issues regarding Opera Software and our products, or privacy on our Web sites please use our contact form

Postal address:  
Opera Software ASA  
P.O. Box 2648 St Hanshaugen  
NO-0131 OSLO  
Norway

## Privacy in the Opera desktop browser

Opera Software has taken much care in the development so that user privacy and security are not compromised. No personal information is collected or shared. The Opera user's Web usage is not tracked.

### Opera's built-in Web search

Opera has a built-in Web search feature. This gives the user the option to utilize external Web search engines directly from the browser interface. Opera relies on third parties for this service. Follow the link below for more information about Opera's search feature.

Please see [www.opera.com/privacy](http://www.opera.com/privacy/) for Opera Software's general privacy policies.

## Privacy in the Opera Mini browser

Opera Mini will keep a record of the user's phone number, make, and model for use with maintaining the history, cache and cookies. This is done for the purposes of debugging, maintenance, optimization of the service, or maintaining the customer relationship. The history, cache and cookie information can be removed using Tools > History > Clear from the menu in Opera Mini.

### Opera Mini's built-in Web search

Opera Mini has a built-in Web search feature. This gives the user the option to utilize external Web search engines directly from the browser interface. Opera Mini relies on third parties for this service. Opera Mini sends the user's search requests (in a specially designed URL string) directly to third party Web sites which handle the actual search queries. What is sent to the third party site is the special Opera Mini search string along with the text terms needed to perform the particular search query. No personal information is sent.

When using the built-in search-related features, Opera Mini will receive cookies, including third party cookies, from thirds party sites. These can be removed using Tools > History > Clear from the menu in Opera Mini.

Some third party sites may monitor data traffic from copies of the Opera Mini browser, such as numbers of hits and the search terms used. No personally identifiable information is made available to these services by the Opera Mini browser nor by Opera Software.

Please note: Opera Software does not control the privacy and security practices and policies of these third parties and their sites. Check the particular site and/or business for more information. It is the responsibility of the browser user to use caution before sharing personal information via forms and other methods used by third parties and their Websites.

Please see [www.opera.com/privacy](http://www.opera.com/privacy/) for Opera Software's general privacy policies.

## Privacy on MyOpera.com 

Opera Software strictly protects the security of your personal information within the confines of the My Opera domain, and honors your choices for its intended use. We carefully protect your data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, alteration, or destruction. All My Opera users should also handle their and other person's personal information with care. We protect your data from disclosure, with exception only in matters where designated by law or court order.

### Information Collected and Shared IP Addresses

Opera Software collects visitors' IP addresses to help diagnose problems with servers, to administer Web sites, and for statistical purposes (aggregated). IP addresses will not be shared to other than Opera Software's partner for handling statistical analyses (see further information below under "Partners") or used for any purposes other than these.

### Voluntary Information Sources

My Opera supports functions that require the submission of relatively personal information given the user's choice of participation. These submissions are gathered by means of forms, surveys, contests, forums, subscribing or unsubscribing mailings and correcting or updating personal information and are only used for their presented purpose. Forms which require financial information to process purchases for products or services are also protected.

### Links to Other Sites

y.Opera.com contain links to other sites. Opera Software is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

### Child Protection

Opera Software provides interactive environments on the Internet to enable members to express themselves and share their ideas and interests by creating and participating in discussion-based virtual communities. Opera.com, Opera.no, and OperaSoftware.com make no guarantees that children can not enter these sites and present both online and offline contact information without parental consent or notification. Further, there is no guarantee that children will not post such information in a public forum. Therefore, we encourage children to include their parents in the registration process, and we encourage parents to get familiar with relevant privacy and data security laws and regulations and to read this privacy statement before allowing their children on line.

### Choice/opt-out

My.Opera.com provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from Opera Software and its partners at the point where information is requested about the visitor. Opera Software gives users the following options for removing their information from our database in order to not receive future communications:

  * Visitors can send e-mail to [list-admin@opera.com](mailto:list-admin@opera.com) list-admin[at]opera.com
  * Visitors can visit the following URL: [list.opera.com](http://list.opera.com/)
  * Visitors can send mail to the following postal address: 
    * Opera Software ASA
    * Waldemar Thranesgt. 98
    * N-0175 OSLO
    * Norway
  * Visitors can call the following telephone number: +47 24 16 40 00

### Correction, Updating or Deletion of Personal Information

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided:

To change your My Opera membership, login to your account and click the Account link at the top of the page.

  * Furthermore, users have the following options for changing , modifying and requesting deletion of information previously provided: form
  * All visitors can send mail to the postal address listed on the contact pages
  * Visitors can send mail to the following postal address: 
    * Opera Software ASA
    * Waldemar Thranesgt. 98
    * N-0175 OSLO
    * Norway
  * All visitors can call the following telephone number: +47 24 16 40 00

### Privacy of customer data

If a customer places a request for customer service, the information that may be collected is: e-mail address, name, phone number, correspondence records, and technical information such as system hardware, operating system, and the version of Opera being used. This information is voluntarily given by the customer, and is used by Opera Software only for the purpose of assisting the customer with his or her problems. This information is not used for any other purpose. Information collected by our customer service department is not shared nor it is sold to other parties. We do not sell or share this information with our advertising partners or advertising agencies.

### Questions?

Please use our contact form if you got questions about this privacy statement, privacy issues regarding Opera Software and our products, or privacy on our Web sites.

Please see [www.opera.com/privacy](http://www.opera.com/privacy/) for Opera Software's general privacy policies.

## Privacy Statement for Opera Web Mail

Opera Software has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. This statement discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for Opera Web Mail.

This privacy statement does not include privacy information for the websites:

  * My.Opera
  * Opera.com
  * Opera.no
  * OperaSoftware.com

Please consult the privacy statements of My Opera or Opera.com, Opera.no, and OperaSoftware.com for information regarding their privacy policies.

### Collection of IP Addresses

Opera Software collects visitors' IP addresses to help diagnose problems with servers and to administer Web sites. IP addresses will not be used for any purposes other than these.

### Information collected from registration forms

Opera Web Mail's registration form requires visitors to provide contact information (e.g. e-mail addresses or telephone numbers) and demographic information (e.g. age, occupation). Visitors' contact information is used to get in touch with them when necessary. Demographic data is used to tailor visitors' experience at the site.

### Links 

Opera Web Mail contains links to other sites. Opera Software is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

Please see [www.opera.com/privacy](http://www.opera.com/privacy/) for Opera Software's general privacy policies.

If a customer places a request for customer service from Opera Software, the information that may be collected is: e-mail address, name, phone number, correspondence records, and technical information such as system hardware, operating system, and the version of Opera being used. This information is voluntarily given by the customer, and is used by Opera Software only for the purpose of assisting the customer with his or her problems. This information is not used for any other purpose. Information collected by our customer service department is not shared nor is it sold to other parties. We do not sell or share this information with our advertising partners or advertising agencies.

## Privacy on Our Web Sites

The following statement discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for Opera.com, Opera.no, and OperaSoftware.com. This privacy statement does not include privacy information for the Web sites My Opera or Opera Web Mail. Please consult the privacy statements of My Opera or Opera Web Mail for information regarding their privacy policies.

### Collection of data

#### IP Addresses

Opera Software will on occasion collect visitors' IP addresses to help diagnose problems with servers and to administer Web sites. IP addresses will not be used for any purposes other than these.

#### Information collected from forms

Opera.com, Opera.no, and OperaSoftware.com use forms for visitors to request information, products, and services. Depending on the the service, product, or information visitors request, visitors' contact information (e.g. e-mail addresses or telephone numbers) or financial information (e.g. credit card numbers) may be collected. Contact information from these forms is used to send orders and information about Opera Software to customers. Visitors' contact information is also used to get in touch with them when necessary. Visitors may opt out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section. Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services.

#### Cookies

Opera.com, Opera.no, and OperaSoftware.com generally do not use cookies, with the following exceptions: The pages on support.opera.no and support.opera.com, called "The Opera Software Support Desk", use technology created by eJournal, which employs cookies to make the service function smoothly. For more information about eJournal, see the links below. Elsewhere on Opera Software's support site, one may encounter the option to voluntarily save a cookie used for subsequent visits. Opera Software does not have access to any information about visitors from cookies received while visiting Opera Software's sites.

#### Survey 

Opera Software's online surveys ask visitors for demographic information (e.g. age, internet usage, or income level). This is not personally-identifying information and is used to tailor visitors' experience at Opera.com, Opera.no, and OperaSoftware.com.

#### Contests

Opera Software runs contests on Opera.com, Opera.no, and OperaSoftware.com in which visitors are requested to provide contact information (e.g. e-mail addresses). Visitors' contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary. This information will not be shared with or sold to other parties. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section.

#### Contests

Opera Software runs contests on Opera.com, Opera.no, and OperaSoftware.com in which visitors are requested to provide contact information (e.g. e-mail addresses). Visitors' contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary. This information will not be shared with or sold to other parties. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section.

#### Public forums

These sites make a Web forum, mailing lists, and news groups available to visitors. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information, and visitors should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information.

### Unsubscribing from mailings

Visitors may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section.

### Links to other sites

Opera.com, Opera.no, and OperaSoftware.com contain links to other sites. Opera Software is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

### Choice/opt-out

Opera.com, Opera.no, and OperaSoftware.com provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from Opera Software and its partners at the point where information is requested about the visitor. Opera Software gives users the following options for removing their information from our database in order to not receive future communications:

  * Visitors can send e-mail to [list-admin@opera.com](mailto:list-admin@opera.com) list-admin[at]opera.com
  * Visitors can visit the following URL: [list.opera.com](http://list.opera.com/)
  * Visitors can send mail to the postal address listed at the bottom of this page.
  * Visitors can call the following telephone number: +47 24 16 40 00

## Privacy of customer data

In order to process the purchases of licenses for copies of our software, certain information is necessarily collected by Opera Software. We retain records of licensed users of our software, and these records may contain any or all of the following information: names, addresses, phone numbers, credit card numbers, or other relative identifying information. We do not sell or share this information with other parties. We do not sell or share this information with our advertising partners or advertising agencies.

If a customer places a request for customer service, the information that may be collected is: e-mail address, name, phone number, correspondence records, and technical information such as system hardware, operating system, and the version of Opera being used. This information is voluntarily given by the customer, and is used by Opera Software only for the purpose of assisting the customer with his or her problems. This information is not used for any other purpose. Information collected by our customer service department is not shared nor it is sold to other parties. We do not sell or share this information with our advertising partners or advertising agencies.
